LAUGHING MAN FANSUBS
I'm a soldier - that means I'm
Both a defendant and the judge
I am standing on both ends of the flame
Rounding curves
Overtaking life and death,
I run and fight with false shadows
No matter how many threads of
deception are woven together,
The truth shall illuminate
the face of light
Save your tears for the day
When our pain is far behind
On your feet, come with me
We are soldiers stand or die
Save your fears, take your place
Save them for the judgement day
Fast and free, follow me
Time to make the sacrifice.
We rise or fall
HQ, I have returned from the Peninsula.
I have some interesting information about Kuze.
The Chief and the Major have been summoned
by the Prime Minister, so they're not here.
They told me to listen to your report.
What situation has a higher
priority than my investigation?
Well, now there's the possibility that
the refugees are planning a mass uprising.
Damn, that's not good...
The Fact of
Being There
Refugee
Measure
Emergency
Conference
Following the uproar over the mass
suicide of the Individual Eleven,
there are reports that refugees throughout
Japan are gathering at Dejima in Nagasaki
in response to the rapidly escalating
anti-refugee demonstration.
The media has been recklessly fanning the flames
by saying that it is a prelude to a mass uprising.
Is there any information that can
shed some light on this matter?
I have received reports that
there have been increasing numbers
of people being apprehended
for illegal entry into Dejima,
but I think it's premature to
link that with a mass uprising.
We are able to stop the influx of
refugees into Nagasaki at the waterfront.
It seems you are ignoring certain realities.
This month, the Coast Guard
has prevented two large ships and sixteen
smaller boats from docking in Dejima.
It's obvious that there is an
influx of refugees into Nagasaki.
I see.
Well, we have many matters
that require our attention.
The particularists?
Then I'd like to know what
Public Safety has been doing.
since they bear the responsibility for letting the
particularists who triggered this event run amok.
Regarding the mass suicide
of the Individual Eleven,
it's unreasonable to have demanded that Public
Safety be aware of all their locations at all times.
After all, even though the
particularists praise the actions
of the Individual Eleven, they maintain
that the Eleven were a league of their own.
In any case, I think that the Ministry of Defence is
the one responsible for the current refugee situation
After all, their desire to
further armament procurement
led them to conduct a live-ammunition
exercise right in front of the refugees,
which stirred them to action.
If you want to start a chicken-or-egg
argument, we'll accept the challenge anytime,
but isn't it your security department that's
wrangling over jurisdiction, even now?
Well, if you're going take that position,
why is the Maritime Self-Defence
Force turning a blind eye?
Before you bring out the jurisdiction issues,
I'd like them to be just a bit more cooperative,
considering we're the ones
putting our lives on the line!
At this point in time,
my understanding is that we have been
granted jurisdiction in this refugee matter.
Listen to yourself!
Remember the security-treaty struggle
of the previous century?
Unfortunately for the pro-MoD Diet
members who came late to the table,
the police will see to upholding
security this time around as well.
Such debates are important, but right now,
reaching a consensus among
the major agencies is crucial.
Let us break for a moment.
It seems you do not even have
the time to bolster your spirits.
It's partly due to my lack of skill,
but if everyone remains fixated on their own
interests, they'll lose sight of the real issue...
even though now is the time they must cooperate
with each other to deal with the refugee problem...
Prime Minister,
do you know the biggest reason why a nation's
military and intelligence agencies deteriorate?
It is exactly as you just said.
Gradual death begins
when the leaders of an organisation
starts to use his organisation
as an instrument for furthering his own interests.
I do feel sorry for making the
Coast Guard do the dirty work...
Well, we cannot be certain that we won't
be blessed with that misfortune ourselves.
That's true enough.
By the way,
have you obtained any specific information
regarding the refugee's actions?
Yes.
Have you heard of "hub cyberbrains"?
No.
Major, please explain.
Prime Minister, may I link directly with you?
Yes.
Originally, the concept of a hub,
or centre, did not exist in the network.
However, a phenomenon was recently observed
where a host establishes a
type of collaborative entity
by defining a direction for
isolated entities on the network
and inviting them into his cyberbrain.
Until now, this was only
observed at a small scale:
communes that formed around small religious
organisations and charismatic artists.
Now, however,
someone among the refugees has emerged
who is able to placate them and
persuade them to stay in this fashion.
We believe this is the reason behind
the influx of refugees to Nagasaki.
Is this the work of one person...
perhaps, the leader?
Logically speaking, it would be difficult
to imagine that it is just one person.
We cannot be sure,
but it seems impossible that any single cyberbrain
has the ability to let the consciousness of
three million people harmonise simultaneously.
However, if we were to construe
this construct as a leader,
then yes, we could say that
he is something like one.
I see.
The emergence of such a person would
be a grave threat to the government.
Please remain on alert.
Understood.
I was hoping to suppress refugee interests
and resolve issues from the taxation system side
by repealing the Refugee Special Treatment Act.
It must mean that there was a political
enemy who used that to his advantage.
Do not let it affect you too much.
Actually...
I have one more thing I'd like you to investigate.
What is that?
In regard to the security pact,
it seems there are some pro-MoD Diet members
who are in collusion with
the former Dai-Nippon Giken.
I believe that the significance
of this security pact
lies in the fact that our country, as the only nation
in the world to possess radiation removal technology,
may gain equal, if not superior,
footing with the American Empire.
The AE has been dependent on nuclear deterrence.
If that is no longer viable,
I am willing to postpone the security pact.
However, some of the Diet
members and captains of industry
do not care about such principles.
If this continues,
our nation will never become independent!
Where did you obtain that information?
From a source in the Ministry of Foreign Affairs.
Then we will investigate the cash flow right away.
Just one thing...
Are you issuing this order for
your own personal interests,
or to preserve a political ideology?
There is no need for an answer.
Understood.
I should've realised this sooner.
Prime Minister Kayabuki is exactly
the type of person you like, Chief.
What, you only realised this now?
I can't beat you, Chief.
By pro-MoD Diet members... she was talking about
Chief Cabinet Secretary Takakura, right?
Probably.
I'd find it difficult to believe
he's doing this just for money.
Takakura is pro-America and pro-right-wing, no?
Yes.
He is an old-timer in the military industrial complex who
has yet to discard blind trust in the American Empire.
From his point of view,
we can increase the value of the radiation removal
technology, which lost value after the war ended,
by joining forces with the American Empire and using
it as a new deterrent force against other nations.
By doing that, he can secure bribes
and also save face for the right wing
without having to pursue
further armament expansion.
That's very different from the
independence-cooperation route
that Prime Minister Kayabuki is arguing for.
He's the top guy in the Cabinet
Intelligence Agency as well, isn't he?
Besides, Gouda has a history of having overseen
the production of the Japanese Miracle at
the former Dai-Nippon Giken.
Inducing terrorism by refugees,
the AE-Japan security pact, and nuclear power...
Looks like her revenge...
is worthy of our assistance.
We're tired of waiting for
you, Prime Minister Kayabuki.
I will be there immediately.
Senpai!
What's up, Azuma?
We haven't been summoned...
is it really okay for us not to join in?
What about the investigation
on the Individual Eleven?
They are less active than the refugees,
so we kind of thought they
were, you know, boring...
You idiots!
What do you mean, "boring"?!
It's your job!
Jeez, you guys have a long way to go!
Back then, the pointless war over Eurasian
hegemony had only just ended, after all...
I snuck into the Peninsula
a couple of times back then,
but it was already pretty modernised.
Did you guys start already?
Not yet.
I was doing warm-up exercises
while waiting for you.
Let's get started.
My sympathies for having to work
overtime so soon after coming back.
Here.
Thank you.
In the year 2024, when nations were
exhausted from the fourth world war,
the American Empire called for the deployment
of UN troops to the Peninsula,
where internal conflict still continued.
That action triggered our SDF deployment, but...
Actually, the American Empire started its
resurrection as the world's dominant power
by using the deployment as a
way to obtain excavation rights
to the uranium mines in the Northern
Peninsula from the unified government, right?
There's that side to it, yeah.
But despite the fact that the
Empire's intentions were transparent,
Japan couldn't have possibly refused the UN, considering
how enthused it was about wartime military procurement.
Thus, this became the first trial for the SDF,
which had been able to avoid actual combat
throughout two world wars,
aside from the recapture of Nemuro.
But people like you and the Major
were overseas unofficially during the
war, weren't they?
Well, yeah.
It's too bad that the Prime Minister at
the time was killed by a terrorist bomb,
since he was one of the few politicians
who had an international perspective.
Because of these behind the scenes issues,
the government had strict control of the
media in order to suppress domestic opinion
and decided to deploy the PKF to Shinuiju
State, which was thought to be relatively safe.
I can still remember the uproar then,
but I guess I gradually grew disinterested
as the news kept showing the SDF,
spending time with the residents,
and looking out of place.
Not surprising.
The reality of it was rather
different, actually...
The agency that worked behind
the scenes to control the media
was the current Cabinet
Intelligence Agency's predecessor,
the Cabinet Press Agency,
So, what was the reality for the PKF?
Oh, yeah...
It seems it was much worse than we'd thought.
Kuze was stationed with the
last mobile company to arrive.
At the time, Shinuiju was a Special
Administrative Region and a trade centre,
making it exempt from attacks.
But after the unified government was established,
the remnants of the defeated People's
Army chose as their battlefield
a rural area about twenty
kilometres east of Shinuiju.
After you cross the border,
I guess it's all mountains.
More like a mountain pass.
The altitude was 800 metres, at most.
So, it was ideal for guerilla warfare.
Soon after the cyborg infantry
arrived, it was decided that two
units would be deployed as a
counter-guerilla punitive force,
so they began moving into the frigid mountains.
This was the first time units were equipped
with hybrid cyborgs on the battlefield,
but the PKF-spec hybrid cyborgs would
not have experienced much discomfort,
even while advancing through
snow in -20°C weather.
At the time,
the main infantry was on
heightened alert after receiving an
intelligence report that the last
elite troops of the People's Army
were plotting to attack Shinuiju State.
Kuze's company was to circle north,
around the enemy, and launch a preemptive strike.
However, on the way,
Kuze's platoon found a refugee camp
along a river on the border that was not
mentioned in the intelligence report.
The camp was being looted by soldiers
of the People's Army who had,
for all intents and purposes, become bandits.
Seeing this happen before their eyes,
the platoon was spurred into
combat by moral indignation.
While there were only thirty of them
against one hundred and twenty soldiers,
the fighting quickly reached a conclusion.
Kuze's platoon was a group
of elites with cyborg bodies,
while those who were attacking the
camp were mostly unarmed and starved,
even if they were former soldiers.
After that, the PKF received several
reports on the People's Army,
but that was their only actual combat.
They were forced to stay on
alert due to the extreme cold
and the possibility of a
guerilla attack at any time,
but for the main infantry
positioned back in the city,
the tension was not that great.
That's the footage I remember seeing.
Yeah.
But after a while, a problem surfaced
in the platoon camp out in the farmland:
PTSD, huh.
Yeah.
Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder.
The experience of having massacred people in their first
fight, not to mention the fact that it was very uneven,
began to eat away at the young soldiers.
Those who still had their
original lungs and other organs
tried synthetic alcohol and hashish
that had been brought in by refugees,
desperate to escape the nightmarish
flashbacks of the massacre.
When order gradually began
to break down in the SDF,
the Japanese media pelted them
with insensitive comments.
The massacre at the refugee camp had
not reached the media due to censorship,
but their criticism of the men's behaviour
was all the more severe because of it.
In addition, their freedom was restricted by
policies designed to prevent the men's disgrace
from reaching the media.
They were even barred from returning to Japan.
Sounds almost like an isolation ward...
Yeah, on top of that,
the refugee camp massacre near the
border was leaked to part of the media
and a false rumour that it had been
executed by the JSDF began to circulate.
The farmers vehemently condemned the
JSDF and demanded an explanation.
However, under the media censorship
neither the young soldiers
nor even their superior officers
could defend themselves.
They could only retreat to their tents.
One day, after these conditions
had gone on for a while,
one of the local journalists apparently
made a comment to one of the soldiers.
He probably thought
he was just making a sarcastic comment to
a soldier who no longer had his own lungs.
Hey!
You there.
do you know the meaning of the word "assassin"?
It's an Arabic word for someone who eats hashish.
The Muslim assassins, who killed the Crusaders
that recaptured Jerusalem in the eleventh century,
attacked while in a dream like
haze after smoking hashish.
The Crusaders then called them
"assassins" and feared them.
Did you guys see this as paradise
because of that stuff, too?
How long will you consider yourselves as guests
after invading someone else's country,
eh, you murderers?
Wh-What?
True...
maybe we did think of ourselves as guests.
Can you give me that... for this?
Kuze then changed his rifle for the
camera and entered the refugee camp.
And, what'd he do?
Nothing.
He just carried the camera around and observed
the refugees lives through the finder,
as well as making origami figures.
I don't get it.
Yeah.
I have no idea what his real intentions were.
But a while after he entered the
camp, strange things began to happen.
First, the elderly gradually became interested
in Kuze and started offering him drinks.
Next the children began asking him
to fold paper planes, and so on.
The refugees drew closer and closer to
Kuze, who didn't say a single word.
By the next day, women as well as
men would take turns talking to him.
Kuze would just happily watch them,
and sometimes, take their pictures.
I see.
And them?
Kuze continued doing this until three months later
when the People's Army surrendered and
the SDF was cleared of its obligations.
Everyone in the media stopped talking
about the massacre after that.
The day before the SDF was to return to
Japan, Kuze disappeared from the camp.
A photo was left at the camp.
What about his whereabouts after that?
He supposedly crossed the border and went west,
but this is not certain either.
While I was investigating where
he wandered and what he was doing,
I interviewed a man who had returned
from a Taiwanese refugee city.
He said he saw a man who
might have been Kuze there.
The hair on his cybernetic body
had turned completely white,
but he was definitely Kuze,
according to the witness.
As "proof", there were always
people hanging around that man
who looked like they were enjoying themselves.
Are you of Japanese descent?
Yes.
Oh. You can speak?
Oh, you are back, Major?
Yes. I was listening.
It's an interesting story, to be sure.
Representative.
The hub cyberbrain's filtering
array proved difficult.
but we finally managed to reverse-trace
the refugees' cyberbrains.
As we'd thought, it seems to be Dejima.
We have requested the NSA to corroborate this,
so we should be able to get
visual confirmation soon.
Finding out a galaxy
of planets and stars within me.
Listening to each of them
singing the same silent melody.
I've never seen such beauty
in possibility...
No smack of doubt or fear.
(Wake up)
I hear a voice.
(And show the light)
hear a voice calling out to me.
(Wake up)
I see inside
(the time is right)
see the light now ever holding me.
All the truth,
(All the truth)
All I need,
to make all this reality.
(it's inside)
The beauty within the shell.
(deep within the shell)
(within the shell)
(Wake up)
I hear a voice
(And show the light)
hear a voice calling out to me.
(Wake up)
(the time is now)
I see inside,
see the light now ever holding me.
All the truth,
(All the truth)
all I need,
to make all this reality,
it's inside
right here within the shell.